# ADAM WANNINGER

adam@awanninger.com · ajwann.com · Columbus, OH

#### SUMMARY

Software Engineering Lead with more than five years of experience developing features and overseeing integrations for enterprise-level applications at Fortune 500 companies and two years shaping team collaboration models and managing a distributed team of developers through all phases of the software development lifecycle. Strong history of building relationships with internal partners and stakeholders and influencing feature/product development.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Application Architecture UX Design Ruby on Rails JavaScript

Node Agile Methodologies MVP Development Technical Leadership

Ruby Ember ES2015+ React

### **EXPERIENCE**

2012 - Present JPMorgan Chase & Co. Columbus, OH

Software Engineering Lead

2018 - Present

- Lead a team of four software engineers, one QA engineer and one technical analyst in resolving critical projects for an access management application, as well as oversee the design and creation of new features to enhance existing controls application for more than 350,000 assets across all business lines for a national Fortune 500 bank
- Designed and implemented a 'Mainframe Account' feature, which allows users to request access to any of the firm's 70+ Mainframes and grants access through an automated process (previously granted manually)
- Led developers in the design of React-based and Ruby on Rails-integrated security and compliance feature which allows application owners to define dynamic questions for end-users during access request times, streamlining approval request routing and increasing compliance with firmwide, legal and SOX controls
- Reviewed resumes, conducted phone screenings, and coordinated on-site interviews to select candidates for hire in fulfillment of 14 engineering positions
- Initiated a culture of pairing programming and test-driven development within team, resulting in junior engineers building core skillsets and transitioning to mid-level engineers more rapidly
- Streamlined project delivery timelines by encouraging team collaboration throughout the entire software development lifecycle from presenting ideas and creating demos to implementation and QA testing, decreasing turn-around time from ~6 months to 2 months for feature development

Software Engineer 2015 – 2018

- Serviced access management and controls application for 800,000+ users, maintaining control of applications and databases for hundreds of business lines to ensure SOX compliance
- Created and implemented an application for certificate management which allowed users to request SSL certificates and access to AD/LDAP groups using Ember JS framework
- Designated as lead developer for high-priority projects involving the build of new applications and tools, such as a feature to lock new database accounts in a firmwide password vault which rotates passwords to increase compliance with firmwide controls procedures
- Designed and implemented a React-based 'Secure from the Start' feature which allows new database accounts with privileged access to be instantly secured upon creation and maintain compliance with established controls procedures; feature was built using React and implemented into legacy Ruby on Rails application

 Implemented new functionality which allowed thousands of application firmwide to comply with the rollout of GDPR's "Right to be informed" requirement

Application Support Specialist

2012 - 2014

- Provided end-user support for a mutual funds application, including identifying and resolving erroneous trades, and identifying opportunities for customer management system features/ enhancements
- Supported implementation of a vendor CRM, SalesPage, which notified sales representatives of actions taken on mutual funds for sales and commissions tracking
- Developed a system to track and inform application team of data inconsistencies for remediation by comparing all customer information to FINRA and other databases; system identified hundreds of data inconsistencies a week for correction

2014 – 2015 Nationwide Insurance Columbus, OH

Test Automation Developer

- Designed and wrote ETL workflows and built a data warehouse to act as a centralized data repository, for use by data aggregation tools which enabled data pooling for analytics and reporting
- Automated manual regression testing scripts through use of Ruby, Rspec, Cucumber and Selenium WebDriver, reducing testing times from several days to a matter of minutes
- Trained incoming manual testers with limited coding experience to write automated tests in Rspec and Cucumber testing environments

2006 – 2012 Ohio National Guard Hamilton, OH

Logistics Specialist (S4)

 Coordinated unit movements during travel to ensure safety and timely arrival, and managed inventory valued at over \$1 million

## **EDUCATION**

Miami University Oxford, OH

Bachelor of Science, double major in Business Management and Marketing (2011)